A Guide to the Certificates of Incorporation Collection, Undated
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Certificates of Incorporation Collection, Undated
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 02-04
.25 linear feet
The Certificates of Incorporation Collection consists of .25 linear feet of undated photocopied Virginia State Corporation Commission certificates of incorporation from various Fairfax County, Virginia businesses incorporated between 1943-1949.
Unknown
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Unknown. Appears to have come from the Clerk's Office of the Circuit Court of Fairfax County, Virginia.
Historical and Biographical Information
The Virginia State Corporation Commission serves as the central filing agency for corporations in Virginia. Established by the Virginia Constitution of 1902, the SCC is a regulatory agency vested with judicial, legislative, and executive powers and has authority over utilities, railroads, franchising, securities, and insurance. The Clerk’s Office maintains business entity documents of record.
Scope and Content
The Certificates of Incorporation Collection consists of .25 linear feet of undated photocopied Virginia State Corporation Commission certificates of incorporation from various Fairfax County, Virginia businesses incorporated between 1943-1949. Businesses included are a golf course, cemetery, school, airports, and volunteer fire departments.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Airports - Virginia - Fairfax County; Business enterprises - Virginia - Fairfax County; Volunteer fire departments - Virginia - Fairfax County
Container List
- Alexandria-Virginia Airport, Incorporated, 1944, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexandria Golf and Country Club, Incorporated, 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annandale Poultry Farm, Incorporated, 1944, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annandale Business Men’s Association, 1946, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bailey’s Cross Roads Volunteer Fire Department, 1943, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Beacon Field, Incorporated, 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Fairfax County Agricultural Cooperative Association, 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fairfax Enterprises, Incorporated, 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Fairfax Quarries, Incorporated, 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Forestville Volunteer Fire Department, 1949, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Hillcrest Memorial Park, Incorporated, 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Jefferson Village Addition, Incoporated,1946, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Langley School, 1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Springfield Airport, Incorporated,1945, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)